Rick van der Eijk

General & Motivation

Place of residence: Den Haag Date of birth: 03-04-1986

Phone number: (+31)628258357 Email address: rickvdeijk@gmail.com

Rick van der Eijk is a self-taught frontend developer with a passion for how development and design interact. He has worked for enterprises such as Unilever, the Dutch government, and IBM, but also for startups and other small businesses. Notable hallmarks include work ethic, eagerness to learn, and a keen eye for maintainable code.

Job Experience

Delta-n

Februari 2023 - Present

Frontend Web Developer

- TopDesk Azure DevOps Integration: upgraded a complex Angular codebase, and guided the team to use scrum in the role of Scrum Master.
- Van Eijck Mobility B.V.: added translation features (French, English, German) to a portal app using Angular i18n, and migrated an app for administrators from C# Razor Pages to React.
- Ministry of Foreign Affairs: refactored a complex Angular project to make it easier to maintain for fellow developers, and added features related to the digital identification of foreigners using biometrics.
- Van Eijck Mobility B.V.: coded up a Leaflet-based map in Angular for a roadside assistance application.
- Expertise Centrum Uniek: expanded the functionality of and solved bugs for a complex frontend (Angular) calendar system
- Tech Stack: Angular, RXJS, NGRX, React, MobX, Angular Kendo, Git, Azure, TypeScript, CSS, C#, .NET

Innervate

September 2022 - Present

Freelance Frontend Web Developer

- Led front-end development of an Angular GIS (Geographical Information System) application maintained in Azure using DevOps
- Took over from a senior developer with 10+ years of experience without any loss in code quality as confirmed by the client
- Configured Swagger and expanded the project's API layer

- Created production-ready features for an app that is used by well-known multinationals such as Shell
- Tech stack: Angular, Azure, RXJS, Swagger, DevOps, Javascript, TypeScript, Git, Leaflet

Reflectlab

August 2022 - January 2023

Freelance Fullstack Web & Unity Developer

- Modernized the Php and AngularJS environment of a major ecommerce platform in the agro sector as well as migrating it to React
- Led development on the front-end side in a team of around 5 developers
- Consulted on various aspect of Unity game development as an additional project
- Tech stack: React, Php, Magento, Microservices, Javascript, Sass, Tortoise SVN, Git

Van der Eijk Web Development

January 2020 - Present

Freelance Fullstack Web & Unity Developer

- Built several Wordpress websites for clients
- Coded up a portfolio to demonstrate web development skills: https://portfolio-rick-van-der-eijk.web.app/
- Persevered in making a career change despite the Covid pandemic being at its height

IBM

March 2021 - August 2022

Fullstack developer

- Rijkswaterstaat project: contributed to a new UI in Angular for the Dutch asbestos tracking system in a team of around eight developers
- Unilever Project: led development on the frontend side in a team of around eight developers and designers
- UK Fashion Trust Project: created Python scripts for a Jupyter notebook project in IBM Cloud
- Received stellar feedback and project assessments, and promoted twice via IBMs official, quarterly procedure
- Racked up over 300 hours of education via IBM's online learning portal and earned the status of Champion Learner Gold
- Tech stack: React, Angular, RXJS, Javascript, TypeScript, Swagger, Git, Leaflet, D3 visualization library, Python, Jupyter Notebooks, CSS, Bootstrap, Sass

Vendiro, Leiden Business Developer **July 2019 – December 2019**

Prospex, Amsterdam Inside Sales Rep Oktober 2016 - June 2019

Stichting Zeldzame Ziekten Fonds, Den Haag 2015 - 2016 IT/Backoffice Employee & Fundraiser

- Redesigned a Customer Relationship Management system so that the organization could systemize its fundraising activities
- Helped to realize a completely renovated WordPress website (zzf.nl)

Hobby projects

Web development portfolio: https://portfolio-rick-van-der-eijk.web.app/

Mech Commander Unity/C# project: https://vdeijk.itch.io/mech-commander

Architectural Visualization app: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pKkWU5ql2kY&t=41s

Mars Commander Unity, C# project: https://vdeijk.itch.io/mars-commander

Education

Erasmus University Rotterdam

2005 - 2010

Public Administration, Master Governance And Management Of Complex systems.

VWO Gasthuislaan

1998 - 2004

Specialization Economics & Society

Logic Room

2022-2023

High-end UI Architecture & TDD programme for senior developers that aim to be thought leaders (https://www.logicroom.co/)

Completed Web Development Courses

- The Modern Angular Bootcamp, <u>udemy.com</u>
- Node.js, Express, MongoDB & More: The Complete Bootcamp 2021, udemy.com
- React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux), udemy.com
- React Tutorial and Projects Course, udemy.com
- React Mastering Test Driven Development, <u>udemy.com</u>
- React Styled Components Tutorial and Project Course, <u>udemy.com</u>
- Understanding Typescript 2021 Edition, udemy.com
- The Complete JavaScript Course 2021: From Zero to Expert!, udemy.com
- Node.js, Express, MongoDB & More: The Complete Bootcamp 2021, udemy.com
- Advanced CSS and Sass: Flexbox, Grid, Animations and More!, udemy.com
- Unity Turn Based Strategy, https://www.gamedev.tv/courses/

^{*}Rick has work experience via various parttime and fulltime jobs since the age of 13.